Nibil M S

Email: me@nibil.in / msnibil@gmail.com

Mobile: +91-9495 41 2790

skype: sayyidnibil

·· ··

Summary

I'm a Techno-Functional professional who started my career as the first employee of a startup after completion of my engineering course in Computer Science and Engineering. I started off as a Development Engineer, later on transitioning myself to a managerial role in the second tier leadership of the company while continuing my role as a Product Engineer in the company. In my 5-year stint with the startup, the company grew from 5 to 72 people. I have had the opportunity to experience the initial hiccups, the effective bootstrapping, external investment, acquisition and the growth of the company from multiple roles and perspectives.

I then moved on to a service company which was then bootstrapping and helped in building a team. I also supported them with handling the client interactions. After that I joined Vogo, a small team with high aspirations and is working as the tech lead.

Work Experience

Teach Lead (April 2017 to Present)
Vogo Automotive, Karnataka (<u>www.vogo.in</u>)

- Lead the product team and report to the CTO.
- Interact with COO and operations team and get inputs for the product.
- Do research and check the feasibility of the features.
- Interact with the design team and IOT team (external) and convey the product requirements and make sure that the development is going on in the correct path and pace.
- Define the features and software architecture of the product's version 2.0, and lead the development.
- Do code reviews and appraisals of developers

Head of Software Services (September 2016 to March 2017) Rawdata Technologies, Kerala (<u>www.rawdatatech.com</u>)

- Reporting directly to the CEO, responsible in the handling services around the globe.
- Interact with clients to understand client's requirement, check feasibility & provide best suitable estimation accordingly.
- Deeply involved in recruiting developers into the team.
- Do code reviews and appraisals of developers
- Do coding and teach interns Python and Django.

VP of Data Research (July 2014 to August 2016) Profoundis Labs Private Ltd, Kerala

- Profoundis developed their flagship product (https://vibeapp.co) backed by a Human + Technology
 Hybrid engine which has been acquired by FullContact.
- As there was a need to grow Data Research as a function in the company, I gradually transitioned into a business role with client interactions.
- Directly reporting to Co-founder & Chief of Data Research, I led the operations side of data research function with the whole Data Research Team functionally reporting to me.
- Was also involved deeply in the recruitment, onboarding, training, performance appraisals as the team grew from 10 to 72.
- Part of the team that developed and maintained the internal Django webapp that augmented the Data Research process.
- Python language scripting.

Senior Product Engineer (July 2012 to June 2014)
Profoundis Labs Private Ltd, Kerala (www.profoundis.com)

- Joined Profoundis as the first employee after the first month of the company's inception.
- Reporting directly to the CTO of the company; responsible for the services side of Profoundis which
 was then bootstrapping.
- Worked with clients from Turkey, Middle East and the US including the likes of Vodafone which cumulatively earned over 100,000\$ for the company.
- Mostly worked with Python, Django, HTML and Javascript during this tenure.

Django Developer (August 2011 to June 2012)

As a prodigy of Mr. Kenneth Gonsalves (Chairman, Indian Python Software Society, 2010 2011)

- Worked on multiple projects including development and maintenance of Websites and Web applications in Python/Django.
- Clients included FIDA Kids (an NGO based out of Africa and India), Bamboo Banks (Ooty based hotel) and Ooty Golf Course.

Education

- Bachelor of Technology in Computer Engineering 2007-2011
 Aligarh Muslim University, Aligarh
- Higher Secondary Examination, March 2007
 Govt Higher Secondary School, Kumaranellur
- Technical High School Leaving Certificate, March 2005
 Technical Higher Secondary School, Vattamkulam

Technical Skills

- Programming Languages and Frameworks:
 - Python, Django , Django Rest Framework
- Databases
 - PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite , Elasticsearch, MongoDB
- Operating Systems
 - GNU/Linux : both Redhat & Debian, Mac OS X, All Microsoft Windows Environments.

Management Skills

- Business sense with technology background.
- Leadership, Interpersonal and team skills
- Initiating, leading and optimizing day to day operations of a team at scale.
- Recruiting and building a team

Personal Information

Name : Nibil M S Sex : Male

Address : Needam, Trithala P.O, Palakkad-679534, Kerala, IN

Date of Birth : 06-10-1989 Marital Status : Married

Passport : Indian (#K3080682)

Languages Known : English, Malayalam, Tamil

Declaration

I hereby declare that all information given by me is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Nibil M S